# MONISHA CAROLINE D

### 9176149430

Monisha.caroline7@gmail.com

### **OBJECTIVE**

Seeking a challenging position with that state of art and technology in a cordial atmosphere where my competencies, analytical & hiring capabilities be put in for the successful execution of the project.

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A vibrant, assertive & a fully-fledged seasoned recruiter with 9.5 years of experience, acting as a bridge between the stake holders, Clients & the candidates, eager to use the recruitment tools and candidate's analytical skills to highly contribute for various business requirements and provide personalized service delivery to attain business needs of the organization. Highly motivated, accomplished in sourcing, screening, qualifying, and closing candidates, as well as coordinating interviews and managing a team.

### **SKILLS**

- Attention to details.
- Listening skills
- Time Management
- Team Handling

- Excellent communication
- Human Resource Policies
- On boarding and Documentations
- Feedback Mechanism
- Relationship building

# PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- CBI (Competency Based Interview)
- Feedback coaching & Mentoring

- Effective Communication
- Source pro HR training

## **WORK HISTORY**

Assistant Manager- HR Jun 2022 to Aug 2023 BNP Paribas

- Superintending the Fund accounting, Transversal team, Data Administration, Investment Reporting & Performance verticals in Chennai
- Handled the **Hedge Fund services & Fund accounting** sectors in Mumbai as well.
- Managing end-end recruitment from an Associate to Vice President.
- Successfully orchestrating the functional roles in FA, DA & IRP
- Managing a team of 2, assigning their day-day activities & developing and implementing the timelines to achieve the targets.
- "We rise by lifting others" is the mantra that I diligently follow and provide guidelines and direction for my team to be successful in life.
- Built an excellent rapport with all the business stakeholders through continuous liaison and was able to strike a chord with difficult stakeholders.
- Dexterous in closing almost 80% of the hiring via direct channel.
- Responsible for commencing accommodation requests & actively involved in social media hire
- Displayed strong analytical ability and brought down the vendor hiring to 5%
- Seldom missed to attain CPH and guaranteed that all my hires were within budget.
- With a good understanding of business knowledge and organization culture, was able to take over the whole FA
  vertical within a week.
- Encouraging internal mobility for employees horizontally & vertically to explore new career developments within the organization.
- Actively participated in CSR, HR learning & development events and campus drives.
- Well equipped with cross-cutting, periodical trainings and meticulous on the organization policies & procedures
- Attending biweekly calls & team huddles with business to Fasttrack and bring all the open positions to closure.
- Ready to learn and explore new challenges & willing to be a part of project roles in the future.

## Apr 2021to Jun 2022

# Assistant Manager- HR Sr Executive -HR Oct 2018 to Mar 2021 WNS Global Services

- Effectively managed the BFS hiring in Chennai & Gurgaon
- Driven the whole frontline recruitment for 2 towers in Chennai
- Made **300+ hires** from Apr '21 to Apr '22
- Aligning resources for the hiring process, beginning with screening applicants and interviewing potential
  resources, interacting with clients & stakeholders, followed by making recommendations, writing offer letters
  and negotiating salary & following up until onboarding.
- Bifurcation w.r.t Source goes as 42% from Job portal, 33.5% from LINK, 18.5% from Direct & 6% from Vendor
- Handled 100% frontline hiring in CHN which includes verticals such as Healthcare, Banking & Financial Services, Insurance, Logistics), Utilities and 80 % of the mid-level hiring in Chennai
- Primary contributor for successful go-live of ANZ/US for WSA, FAB, CBD. Was able to deliver all the resources before transition
- Managed most of the mid & senior level recruitment
- Regular rapport/meeting with all the stake holders.
- Successfully trained new team members in a short span, on the recruitment flow in such a way that he/she is capable of taking complete ownership on numbers assigned to him/her.
- Key contributor for the successful execution of go-lives of few projects.
- Hands-on experience in handling mega/huge walk-in drives & volume hiring
- Location Spoc for LINK scheme, Job portals & Smart Recruiter tool, responsible for completing the UAT testing, running the tool & associated for the successful go-live of SR insystem.
- Dealt with hiring for niche complex projects such as actuarial, RPA
- Responsible for sharing the pricing details & Market mapping for all the new projects
- Proven talent in meeting huge numbers within deadline
- Can easily work under pressure & capable of delivering/meeting the numbers within TAT
- Actively recruited from zero cost hiring channels like Face book, LinkedIn
- 2% of vendor contribution in the FY19-20
- Encouraging referrals within the organization to hire reliable resources.
- Initiated the new hire paper work process & pre joining BGV.
- Responsible for booking/ arranging accommodation for outstation candidates
- Sending out hiring trackers on a daily basis and drive transitioncalls.
- Actively involved as a WNS Cares Foundation volunteer, visiting government aided schools, teaching them on a regular basis
- Bagged the League of Champion award multiple times for various achievements
- Abide by the SR protocol & follow 100% compliance that comes along with it.

Executive-HR Dec 2013 to Nov 2016

- Merely responsible for the entire Band A frontline hiring across Chennai
- Hired for various horizontals such as International Voice, Domestic Voice, Language specialist in Voice & Data, Actuarial, AP, AR, GL, Financial Reporting, Procurement, Trade, Consumer Credit, Risk Managements, Hedge Funds, Human Resource Out sourcing,, Quality and R&A.
- Stepped an extra mile & brought the vendor dependency to Zero % from FY '14- FY '16
- Hands-on experience in sourcing & short listing profiles from various jobportals.
- Never missed the deadline/TAT for any requirement during my tenure.
- Posting jobs on a regular basis in social media to reduce the CPHintermittently.
- Encouraging referrals within the organization to hire reliable resources.
- Initiating the new hire paperwork process
- Explaining all of the Human Resources policies, procedures, laws, standards, and regulations to each employee.
- Actively recruiting from zero cost hiring channels like Face book, LinkedIn.

- Connecting for team meeting daily to have regular updates on buffer/pipeline.
- Initiation of pre-joining BGV.
- Responsible for arranging accommodation for outstation candidates.
- Developed and facilitated job recruitment fairs.
- Facilitated all new employee orientations to faster a positive team attitude.
- Tracked key dates and deadlines and maintained specific personal list.
- Promptly corresponded with all applicants and coordinator and connected interviews.
- Led the creation of recruiting plans for all open positions.
- Developed/Negotiated salary proposals for new recruits.
- Posted positions through approved recruitment channels.
- Networked with industry contacts, association memberships, and associates.
- Pre-screened all resumes prior to sending them to corporate hiring managers.
- Partnered with local organizations and university for engagement and interest in jobs offered in their community.
- Tracked candidates and pushed for feedbacks on disqualification, time to fill statistics and other variables.
- Publishing weekly hiring dashboard and analysis to senior managers.
   Managing the weekend recruitment drive, walk-ins, campus recruitment.

# HR Executive TeamLease Services

May 2012 to Dec 2013 (Deputed to WNS Global Services)

- Trained on the hiring strategies & was responsible for the entire frontline hiring for AIRCEL domestic voice process
- Comprehensive experience in Screening, short listing resources through various assessments, building rapport with stakeholders, salary diplomacy, document verification & joining formalities.
- Conduct walk-in drives, post ads, job fairs & actively source talents through Social media
- Responsible for end-end frontline hiring.
- Worked on various lateral positions in Actuarial such as Prophet modeling, GI & Life Insurance.

## **CREDENTIALS**

• B. Tech(Information Technology) from Kings Engg College (2010) with 72%

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Best recruiter of South India within 3 months of joining the company
- Bagged the BFS High Growth award for supporting the largest Client of WNS across globe.
- Awarded the League of Champion award multiple times for delivering relatively huge numbers within deadline
- Appreciated by the clients for being the primary contributor of successful live of 3 leading projects.
- Appreciated by most of the stake holders on quick hiring
- Appreciated by CEO thrice for showcasing my talent during BRAVO programs & other town hall programs
- Zero percent vendor/Consultant contribution from 2014-2016 & 2018-2019 respectively
- All the open positions assigned, were met within the TAT/Deadline during my term.
- Expanded the usage of Social media hiring by 12% which fetched zero cost hiringimpact.
- Supported in implementation of referral schemes across insurance industry.
- Closed the most Niche positions in Actuarial-Insurance
- Created a group in Social media exclusively for Actuaries & posted jobs then & there which brought out right talents & reduced the CPH.

# **CERTIFICATION**

- Certified Competency Based Interviewer
- Certified as Source pro HR Excellence

# **HOBBIES & PASSION**

• Play the keyboard

Singing

• Pencil art

• Photography

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 02 Dec 1988Marital Status : Married

• Languages Known: Tamil, English

I hereby reveal that the above attributes are accurate to my understanding.

Yours loyally

Location: Chennai Monisha Caroline D